#### Contact

+447448424848 (Mobile) rameasy@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rameasy (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

Integration Testing
Behavior-Driven Development (BDD)
Object-Oriented Programming
(OOP)

### Certifications

**SCJP** 

**AWS Essentials** 

**OCWCD** 

Apache Spark for Java developers Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer

Honors-Awards

Apexon Stars UK

# Ramachandran Subramanian

Senior Developer / Sr. Software Engineer / Technical Lead Hatfield, England, United Kingdom

## Summary

I am Ramachandran Subramanian. An Innovative IT professional with 15 years of experience and key strengths in technology design, development and implementation. I consider myself to be highly motivated and able to handle a broad range of tasks, have good problem solving abilities and am hard working and team orientated.

Specialties: Agentic AI, Amazon Web Services, Java, JEE, Swing, Spring Batch, Spring Core, Springboot, REST Services, Apache Spark, JUnit, Scrum, Maven, JSON, Shell scripting, Hibernate, JPA, Web Designing, Web Technologies, Oracle, Tomcat, Hive, HDFS

# Experience

NatWest Group Software Engineer August 2023 - Present (2 years 3 months) London, England, United Kingdom

### Apexon

Senior Developer June 2022 - August 2023 (1 year 3 months) London, England, United Kingdom

As a senior developer I am responsible for the below items.

- 1. Involve in analysis, design, testing and implementation phases of Software Development Life Cycle.
- 2. Communicate effectively within the team and with other teams to complete the tasks.
- 3. Identify and suggest the changes to the application to improve it service and performace.
- 4. Update every changes made in the application in Confluence to make it useful for the future.
- 5. Review the work of other developers and providing feedback.
- 6. Writing extensive tests for each commit, which will be continuously and rapidly verified.

- 7. Developing and deploying REST APIs within serverless architecture.
- 8. Working in collaborative teams and working in an agile manner in a commercial environment.

#### Virtusa

#### Lead Consultant

October 2017 - June 2022 (4 years 9 months)

London, England, United Kingdom

I worked as a lead consultant in Virtusa for around 5 years and during my tenure I worked in multiple projects. To summarize, below were my responsibilities while working in Virtusa.

- 1. Working with developers to ensure quality network frameworks, mentoring junior level staff, and identifying issues that affect product delivery.
- 2. Using coding standards and best practices to ensure quality.
- 3. Identifying risk and conducting mitigation action planning.
- 4. Developing high-quality and detailed designs.
- 5. Providing proper code documentation and implement configuration changes to packaged software applications to meet business requirements.
- 6. Analyze the business users' needs, then design and develop an application or leverage existing technology with customized enhancements to provide a solution.
- 7. Taking end-to-end ownership on the changes through the software development life cycle.
- 8. Active participant in the Agile/Scrum development process, completing assignments in time, and with the necessary quality.
- 9. Worked within a small, highly collaborative team and engaged in pair programming using the extreme programming framework.
- 10. Had the opportunity to coach and mentor junior colleagues and work as part of a well-established, collaborative team.
- 11. Actively participated in knowledge sharing activities, both within the team and at a wider capability level and externally where appropriate.
- 12. Provided support of existing applications to an agreed SLA.

Mercator Solutions Software Development Engineer September 2014 - August 2017 (3 years)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

I worked as software development engineer in Mercator for 3 years. In these three years I worked in two projects and below were my responsibilities during my tenure.

- 1. Producing clean, efficient code based on specifications.
- 2. Testing and deploying programs in multiple testing environments.
- 3. Review the code of peer team members.
- 4. Actively participate in the design discussion and provide valuable feedback.
- 5. Participate in an Agile/Scrum methodology to deliver high-quality software releases.
- 6. Develop comprehensive knowledge of how areas of business integrate to accomplish business goals.

**IBS Software Services** 

Sr. Software Engineer

August 2012 - August 2014 (2 years 1 month)

Thiruvananthapuram Area, India

I worked in IBS Software Services for two years as Senior Software Engineer. During the period my responsibilities were

- 1. Executing full software development & Testing life cycle (SDLC).
- 2. Participating in collaborative technical discussions that focus on software user experience, design, architecture, and development
- 3. Endure deliverable quality without compromising on the timelines.
- 4. Bug fixing and ensuring no blocker and critical bugs to be found in testing.
- 5. Adhere to coding standards and produce high quality code and participate in peer code review.

**Dell Services** 

2 years 8 months

Technical Analysis Sr. Associate

December 2010 - August 2012 (1 year 9 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

I started my career as fresher in Dell Services and worked around 3 years.

Below were my responsibilities during my tenure.

- 1. Designing and implementing Java-based applications.
- 2. Analyzing user requirements to inform application design.
- 3. Contributed to all stages of the software development lifecycle.
- 4. Build features and modules from scratch & Maintain existing features and modules.
- 5. Directly discussed the requirements with client and sent the status reports.

Technician Support
January 2010 - December 2010 (1 year)

- Designing and Implementing CR's and fixing critical bugs to provided stable build releases & patches to the QA and Release Management team.
- Prepared Test Cases Document (UTC) and performed unit testing.
- Providing hot fixes as per business requirement from onsite at the time of UAT.
- Also monitored application and database servers.

### Education

Bannari Amman Institute of Technology

Master of Computer Applications - MCA, Computer Application · (2006 - 2009)

Ramakrishna Mission Vidhyalaya

Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer science · (2003 - 2006)